<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Pirun Seng]]></title>
  <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-10-04T16:44:36+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pirun Seng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setup Docker Machine With VM and Known Issues]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2018/10/04/setup-docker-machine-with-vm-and-known-issues/"/>
    <updated>2018-10-04T16:04:48+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2018/10/04/setup-docker-machine-with-vm-and-known-issues</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi There, today I am going to share steps, but not actually how as I will leave a reference to the Docker docs at the end, to set up Docker Machine and some known issues I have experienced.</p>

<ol>
<li>Install Docker</li>
<li>Install Docker Machine</li>
<li>Download and Install VirtualBox (VirtualBox-5.2.18-124319-OSX.dmg)</li>
<li>Create Docker Machine</li>
<li>Known issues:

<ul>
<li>Failed to install VirtualBox on MacOS. You may find this link helpful; <a href="https://matthewpalmer.net/blog/2017/12/10/install-virtualbox-mac-high-sierra/index.html">How to Install VirtualBox on macOS Mojave and High Sierra</a></li>
<li>Failed to create docker machine. The solution that works for me is just to reboot machine. After reboot, I could create docker machine successfully.</li>
<li>docker: Cannot connect to the Docker daemon at unix:///var/run/docker.sock. Is the docker daemon running? => This means that your Docker is not running. So you may just run your Docker app, and see that it is running. That should fix this problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Reference:</strong> <a href="https://docs.docker.com/machine/install-machine">https://docs.docker.com/machine/install-machine</a></p>

<p>Nice day,</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common Mistakes We Might Make in Rails Development]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2018/08/12/common-mistakes-we-might-make-in-rails-development/"/>
    <updated>2018-08-12T17:21:54+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2018/08/12/common-mistakes-we-might-make-in-rails-development</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>1 - Irreversible Migration</h2>

<p><strong>Rails 3</strong> has introduced <code>change</code> method which help reduces lines of migration code from two method <code>up</code> and <code>down</code> to just one which is <code>change</code> method. For example, we want to change default value of <code>nil</code> to an empty string <code>''</code>.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>def change
</span><span class='line'>  change_column_default :articles, :owner, ''
</span><span class='line'>end</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>There is no problem when we run <code>rake db:migrate</code>. Yet, we don&rsquo;t realize that we have made a mistake until we rollback the migration at some point. Then there will be an exception of <code>ActiveRecord::IrreversibleMigration</code>.</p>

<p>To get rid of the <code>ActiveRecord::IrreversibleMigration</code> exception, we have to rewrite both <code>up</code> and <code>down</code> methods again.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>def up
</span><span class='line'>  change_column_default :articles, :owner, ''
</span><span class='line'>end
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>def down
</span><span class='line'>  change_column_default :articles, :owner, nil
</span><span class='line'>end</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Heh! If you&rsquo;re using <strong>Rails 5</strong>, there is a better way that help improve this case by adding <code>from</code> (old default value or nil) and <code>to</code> (new default value) options.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>def change
</span><span class='line'>  change_column_default :articles, :owner, from: nil, to: ''
</span><span class='line'>end</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>By specifying the <code>from</code> and <code>to</code> options, we can freely run our migrations up and down without getting any of <code>ActiveRecord::IrreversibleMigration</code> exceptions anymore.</p>

<h2>2 - Accidentally Deleted Object(s)</h2>

<p>To be continued&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modify EBS Volume or Disk Space of Amazon EC2]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2018/08/09/modify-ebs-volume-or-disk-space-of-amazon-ec2/"/>
    <updated>2018-08-09T15:23:20+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2018/08/09/modify-ebs-volume-or-disk-space-of-amazon-ec2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon has provided us cool and easy ways to modify EBS volume, or in other word is to modify disk space of our instance or server.</p>

<p>I am going to sum up of how we can achieve it by using AWS Console. However, the <strong>FIRST</strong> thing you need to know is that you <strong>CAN</strong> increase the volume, but <strong>CANNOT</strong> decrease.</p>

<p>Go on if you are about to increase your volume!</p>

<p>If we are running multiple instances and volumes, the first thing we need to know is which volume that is associated with which instance we want to modify.</p>

<p>If we open the <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/ec2/">Amazon EC2</a> console and navigate to <strong>Volumes</strong> page, we will see a list of some volumes if we are running multiple instances. For somebody who has already named their volumes, that is okay for them, but as my first experience, I haven&rsquo;t named any of the volumes, so I don&rsquo;t know which Volume of my instance I am looking for to modify.</p>

<p>Worry not! To know which instance our volume is attached to, just click on the volume, and in the <strong>Description</strong> tab below, we can see the instance in <strong>Attachment information</strong>. After find out the instance it is attached to, I recommend to name your volume at this point, if you haven&rsquo;t, so it is helpful when we come back later and that we can catch it up immediately.</p>

<p>Okay so now we know which volume to be modified! BUT! Wait! It is recommended to create a <strong>Snapshot</strong> of your current volume before modifying.</p>

<p>I will just leave a link for <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/ebs-creating-snapshot.html">How to create a Snapshot</a>. It might take some time due to how big your volume is.</p>

<p>Once you already create a snapshot, then you&rsquo;re ready for modifying the volume.</p>

<p>Let select a volume, and choose the dropdown <strong>Actions</strong> button on the top, and select <strong>Modify Volume</strong>. We will see a modal window of Modify Volume, verify the Volume Type, adjust the size in GiB you like, and click <strong>Modify</strong> button, and <strong>Yes</strong>.</p>

<p>Last, modifying volume size has no effect until we tell the file system to get advantage of new storage size.
This is how you can <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/recognize-expanded-volume-linux.html">Extending a Linux File System after Resizing the Volume</a>.
In my case, I just need to run the following two commands.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>sudo growpart /dev/xvda 1
</span><span class='line'>sudo resize2fs /dev/xvda1</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><strong>Please&hellip;</strong> keep in mind that when we want to modify something like this, eg. Volume (disk space), Data, etc, we do have to do a back-up, like we were creating a <strong>Snapshot</strong> of the volume, so it safe in case we want to rollback or something. Plus, it is <strong>even more better</strong> if you can try it on a test instance and volume first before working on the live one.</p>

<p>Reference: <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/console-modify.html">Modifying an EBS Volume from the Console</a></p>

<p>Cheers,</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous Integration With Codeship]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/12/19/continuous-integration-with-codeship/"/>
    <updated>2017-12-19T08:19:06+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/12/19/continuous-integration-with-codeship</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Codeship</strong> is one of a very cool Continuous Integration (CI) platform. It comes with pre-installed various programming languages, frameworks and dependencies.</p>

<p>With a simple, yet powerful web UI and UX design, it makes us easy to get started in just a few minutes.</p>

<p><strong>Codeship</strong> allows developers to connect to different repositories such as <strong>Github</strong>, <strong>Gitlab</strong> and <strong>Bitbucket</strong>. On top of that, we can setup our testing environment and deployment targets. Whenever the code is pushed to the repository, then <strong>Codeship</strong> gets triggered and run our test. There is an API of the build status in which we can put it in somewhere like the README of our project. We can either enable or disable the build notification on our own.</p>

<p><strong>Codeship Basic is free!!</strong>
Register for a free account, then we are ready to ship our code so that we can sleep well at night.</p>

<h3>Getting started</h3>

<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/codeship/codeship_navbar.png" title="Navbar" ></p>

<p>Assume that we are already signed in. On the top navigation bar, click on <strong>Projects</strong>, you will as the screenshot above, layout might be changed due to current date.</p>

<p>By clicking on <strong>New Project</strong>, you will be asked to choose which repository you want to connect to.</p>

<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/codeship/codeship_repositories.png" title="Repositories" ></p>

<p>In my case, I click on Github and I&rsquo;ll come to this page in which I will have to put corresponding Git clone URL so that my repository and Codeship is connected.</p>

<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/codeship/codeship_connect_repo.png" title="Connect Repository" ></p>

<p>At the project types selection section, click on <strong>Select Basic project</strong></p>

<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/codeship/codeship_select_plan.png" title="Select Project Type" ></p>

<p>Last but not least, we need to choose the setup command. These are the pre-installed languages, frameworks and dependencies as I have mentioned above. Choose the one you are working on. In my case, I will want to choose Ruby on Rails since I&rsquo;m building a web app with Ruby on Rails.</p>

<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/codeship/codeship_setup_command.png" title="Setup Command" ></p>

<p>Click <strong>Save and go to dashboard</strong>, you should see your first build status.</p>

<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/codeship/codeship_build_status.png" title="Build Status" ></p>

<p>The very last step (optional but recommended), we should display the build status on our repository using Codeship build status API. To do so, you might want to click on the build status, then click on <strong>Project Settings</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/codeship/codeship_project_settings.png" title="Project Settings" ></p>

<p>On the <strong>General</strong> tab, and at the <strong>Status Images</strong> section, we can use any of the image we would like to show the current status of our project. In my case, I use the <strong>Markdown Syntax</strong>. I put it in the README of my project, and here how it looks on my Github repository of the project I have connected to Codeship.</p>

<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/codeship/codeship_build_api.png" title="Codeship Build API" ></p>

<p>It has been a long day already, hasn&rsquo;t it?</p>

<p>Hope you enjoy it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Active Record Finder Methods - Find or Find_by]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/11/06/active-record-finder-methods-find-or-find-by/"/>
    <updated>2017-11-06T21:11:24+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/11/06/active-record-finder-methods-find-or-find-by</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There might be sometimes that we get an unexpected exception where we use ActiveRecord::FinderMethods <code>find</code> and <code>find_by</code>.</p>

<p>So we need to be sure whether to use <code>find</code> or <code>find_by</code> where we are finding active record.</p>

<p>The main difference between <code>find</code> and <code>find_by</code> is the answer to this question, <strong>what we want to return once the record is not found?</strong> We will want to use <code>find_by</code> when we want to return <strong><em>nil</em></strong> if no record is found while we use <code>find</code> to expect the exception, <strong><em>ActiveRecord::RecordNotFound</em></strong>, to be raised.</p>

<p>To discover more about Active Record Finder Methods, please refer to the <a href="http://api.rubyonrails.org/classes/ActiveRecord/FinderMethods.html">API document</a>.</p>

<p>Happy coding!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Upload Files From Remote Location With Carrierwave]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/23/how-to-upload-files-from-remote-location-with-carrierwave/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-23T22:24:02+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/23/how-to-upload-files-from-remote-location-with-carrierwave</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Carrierwave</strong> is a classier solution for file uploads for Rails, Sinatra and other Ruby web frameworks.</p>

<p>I am going to demonstrate <strong>How to: Upload files from a remote location to JSONB or Array image column</strong>.
For installation and configuration, I would recommend you to read <a href="https://github.com/carrierwaveuploader/carrierwave">Carrierwave document</a>.</p>

<p>Let say we have an <strong>Avatar</strong> model with an <code>image</code> column of array data type.
To create a new Avatar record with an image:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>avatar = Avatar.new
</span><span class='line'>avatar.remote_image_urls = ['https://image.flaticon.com/icons/png/512/25/25231.png']
</span><span class='line'>avatar.save</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p><strong>Note:</strong> We use <code>remote_image_urls</code> for <strong>jsonb</strong> or <strong>array</strong> data type column while we use <code>remote_image_url</code> for <strong>string</strong> data type column.</p>

<p>Please feel tree to replace <code>image</code> to any column name you use to store the file or image. e.g If your <strong>Avatar</strong> model has a column named <code>photo</code>, then you might want to modify the syntax above to <code>remote_photo_url</code> and <code>remote_photo_urls</code>.</p>

<p>You can dig deeper to its source code <a href="https://github.com/carrierwaveuploader/carrierwave/blob/87c37b706c560de6d01816f9ebaa15ce1c51ed58/lib/carrierwave/mount.rb">here</a>.</p>

<p>Happy coding!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast Finder]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/22/fast-finder/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-22T10:22:57+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/22/fast-finder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a searcher, I usually spend much time looking for what I want and the right thing.
Anyway, I sometimes feel not really good to spend much time looking for the things, but I still cannot find the right resources or solutions.</p>

<p>This makes me create a <em>simple app</em> called <strong>Fast Finder</strong> which <em>records all right resources and solutions</em> I have found. The main objective is to find the right thing faster. I hosted it on <a href="https://www.heroku.com/">Heroku</a>.</p>

<p>Recently, most resources are for <strong>Ruby</strong> and <strong>Ruby on Rails</strong> as I am a Rails Developer. Anyway, it will be for many more languages, programming languages, frameworks and technologies as it is growing and from your contribution.</p>

<p>Check out the link here: <a href="https://fastfinder.herokuapp.com/">Fast Finder</a></p>

<p>Nice day!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Make Use of Library We Use]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/22/make-use-of-library-we-use/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-22T10:12:47+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/22/make-use-of-library-we-use</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was a fresh <strong>Software Developer</strong>, I usually looked for libraries which were suit for programming language I used <strong>Ruby</strong>, in my case.</p>

<p>It is awesome that there is a <strong>Ruby on Rails</strong> which is a framework for <strong>Ruby</strong>. Plus, there are lots of <a href="https://rubygems.org/">Ruby Gems</a> that are designed to help building software with <strong>Ruby</strong> and <strong>Ruby on Rails</strong> as well.</p>

<p>Jump to the point, when I used any Ruby gems, I just built thing with its main and basic usage. Once I came up with an idea to build something more advanced along with that library, my brainstorm was to write the things from scratch. Then, I did research on google for some concepts.</p>

<p>Soon, there was another idea came to my brain. <em>&ldquo;Why didn&rsquo;t I read more document about the library I were using to see whether or not it had what I wanted?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Bang! It was just a few minutes searching the feature in its the document, I found the exactly thing as I wanted.</p>

<p>To sum up, it is good to know what main features exist in the library we use, but it is much better to discover everything it can do.</p>

<p>Happy coding!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Undo Git Merge]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/22/undo-git-merge/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-22T09:52:46+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/22/undo-git-merge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/git.png" title="Git" alt="Git" /></p>

<p><strong>Git</strong> is awesome and that I&rsquo;ve used it along with my career, software development, so far.</p>

<p>I sometimes get confused doing git merge between branches. When it is a tough time preparing to release my feature to test server in which I have to merge the latest master branch, into my current working branch, let say <strong>update-layout</strong> branch.</p>

<p>Unexpectedly, I have merged <strong>update-layout</strong> into <strong>master</strong>. Actually, I want to merge <strong>master</strong> into <strong>update-layout</strong>.</p>

<p>Luckily, I haven&rsquo;t pushed the master yet so that I can revert/undo merge safely.</p>

<p>To undo the merge, it is as simply as the following:</p>

<ul>
<li>Stay on <strong>master</strong> branch by <code>git checkout master</code></li>
<li>Type <code>git log</code> on the terminal to see the commit histories.</li>
<li>Find the latest commit of <strong>master</strong> branch we want to revert to.</li>
<li>Copy the commit <strong>sha</strong>, e.g. <strong>dbf0e49</strong>.</li>
<li>Back to terminal and type <code>git reset --hard dbf0e49</code></li>
<li>It&rsquo;s done! We&rsquo;re on the latest commit as we want to revert/undo merge.</li>
</ul>


<p>If we&rsquo;re ready to merge <strong>update-layout</strong> into <strong>master</strong> or redo merge, it can be done easily for just do the merge again.</p>

<p>Happy with Git!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy File and Entire Directory From Amazon S3 to Local Machine]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/21/copy-file-and-entire-directory-from-amazon-s3/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-21T18:06:56+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/21/copy-file-and-entire-directory-from-amazon-s3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First thing we need to do is to install <strong>Amazon Web Service Command Line Interface</strong> (AWS CLI).</p>

<p>Depending on your environment, there are different ways to <a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/userguide/installing.html">install AWS CLI</a>. I&rsquo;m using Mac OSX, and I prefer to install it via Homebrew <code>brew install awscli</code>.</p>

<p>Then we need to configure awscli by running: <code>aws configure</code>. You will be prompted to put your AWS Access Key Id, Secret Key, Region and Output. The following is an example:</p>

<pre><code>Access key : foo
Secret key : bar
Region     : us-west-1
Output     : json
</code></pre>

<p>We are all set. Now, I gonna show you how we copy a specific file and an entire directory from Amazon S3.</p>

<p><strong>Copy a file : </strong> <code>aws s3 cp s3://bucket_name/dir/file.png local_path</code></p>

<p><strong>Copy a directory : </strong> <code>aws s3 cp --recursive s3://bucket_name/dir local_path</code></p>

<p>The example above, I show you how to copy a file, &lsquo;file.png&rsquo;, and an entire directory, &lsquo;dir&rsquo;, by specifying <code>--recursive</code> option from Amazon S3 to your local machine or directory where you specify <code>local_path</code>.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backup and Restore Postgres Database From Amazon RDS]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/20/backup-and-restore-postgres-database-from-amazon-rds/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-20T16:59:33+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/20/backup-and-restore-postgres-database-from-amazon-rds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are two things might happen when we do the backup and restore database. We need to know whether the database is located in local server or in any separate server like RDS.</p>

<p>Here, I&rsquo;d like to raise two ways of backup Postgres database. One is the local database, and other one is the separate database.</p>

<p><strong>Local Database</strong></p>

<pre><code>Backup: pg_dump -n schema_name -d db_name &gt; backup_filename.dump

Restore: psql db_name &lt; backup_filename.dump
</code></pre>

<p><strong>Host Database (Amazon RDS)</strong> (You will be prompted to type your database password.)</p>

<pre><code>Backup: pg_dump -h db_host -p db_port -U db_user -n schema_name -d db_name &gt; backup_filename.dump

Restore: psql db_name -h db_host -p db_port -U db_user &lt; backup_filename.dump
</code></pre>

<p>You should notice that we need to specify database host, port and user if we have the database setup in a host server, Amazon RDS in my case. That is the important point that some developers might forget.</p>

<p>For further detail of the other backup and restore options, please refer to the <a href="https://www.postgresql.org/docs/">PostgreSQL docs</a> and look for database backup and that applies to the Postgres version you use.</p>

<p>Enjoy your DBA time!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dump Postgres Data From Specific Table]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/20/dump-postgres-data-from-specific-table/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-20T15:59:56+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/20/dump-postgres-data-from-specific-table</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re in a hurry to make your code work as expected, and you don&rsquo;t prefer to read the document much, we have something in common. And this article is right for you.</p>

<p><img class="[test]" src="http://pirunseng.github.io/images/pg/dump_table.png" title="Dump Table" ></p>

<p>If we haven&rsquo;t read the note of the document as the screenshot above, then we missed something. And what we missed is the prefix schema name on our table name. So, instead of <code>-n schema_name -t table_name</code>, we should use this <code>-t schema_name.table_name</code>.</p>

<p>Happy coding!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
