<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Aws | Pirun Seng]]></title>
  <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/categories/aws/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-09-04T11:58:12+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pirun Seng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Modify EBS Volume or Disk Space of Amazon EC2]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2018/08/09/modify-ebs-volume-or-disk-space-of-amazon-ec2/"/>
    <updated>2018-08-09T15:23:20+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2018/08/09/modify-ebs-volume-or-disk-space-of-amazon-ec2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazon has provided us cool and easy ways to modify EBS volume, or in other word is to modify disk space of our instance or server.</p>

<p>I am going to sum up of how we can achieve it by using AWS Console. However, the <strong>FIRST</strong> thing you need to know is that you <strong>CAN</strong> increase the volume, but <strong>CANNOT</strong> decrease.</p>

<p>Go on if you are about to increase your volume!</p>

<p>If we are running multiple instances and volumes, the first thing we need to know is which volume that is associated with which instance we want to modify.</p>

<p>If we open the <a href="https://console.aws.amazon.com/ec2/">Amazon EC2</a> console and navigate to <strong>Volumes</strong> page, we will see a list of some volumes if we are running multiple instances. For somebody who has already named their volumes, that is okay for them, but as my first experience, I haven&rsquo;t named any of the volumes, so I don&rsquo;t know which Volume of my instance I am looking for to modify.</p>

<p>Worry not! To know which instance our volume is attached to, just click on the volume, and in the <strong>Description</strong> tab below, we can see the instance in <strong>Attachment information</strong>. After find out the instance it is attached to, I recommend to name your volume at this point, if you haven&rsquo;t, so it is helpful when we come back later and that we can catch it up immediately.</p>

<p>Okay so now we know which volume to be modified! BUT! Wait! It is recommended to create a <strong>Snapshot</strong> of your current volume before modifying.</p>

<p>I will just leave a link for <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/ebs-creating-snapshot.html">How to create a Snapshot</a>. It might take some time due to how big your volume is.</p>

<p>Once you already create a snapshot, then you&rsquo;re ready for modifying the volume.</p>

<p>Let select a volume, and choose the dropdown <strong>Actions</strong> button on the top, and select <strong>Modify Volume</strong>. We will see a modal window of Modify Volume, verify the Volume Type, adjust the size in GiB you like, and click <strong>Modify</strong> button, and <strong>Yes</strong>.</p>

<p>Last, modifying volume size has no effect until we tell the file system to get advantage of new storage size.
This is how you can <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/recognize-expanded-volume-linux.html">Extending a Linux File System after Resizing the Volume</a>.
In my case, I just need to run the following two commands.
<code>
sudo growpart /dev/xvda 1
sudo resize2fs /dev/xvda1
</code></p>

<p><strong>Please&hellip;</strong> keep in mind that when we want to modify something like this, eg. Volume (disk space), Data, etc, we do have to do a back-up, like we were creating a <strong>Snapshot</strong> of the volume, so it safe in case we want to rollback or something. Plus, it is <strong>even more better</strong> if you can try it on a test instance and volume first before working on the live one.</p>

<p>Reference: <a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/console-modify.html">Modifying an EBS Volume from the Console</a></p>

<p>Cheers,</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copy File and Entire Directory From Amazon S3 to Local Machine]]></title>
    <link href="http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/21/copy-file-and-entire-directory-from-amazon-s3/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-21T18:06:56+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://pirunseng.github.io/blog/2017/10/21/copy-file-and-entire-directory-from-amazon-s3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First thing we need to do is to install <strong>Amazon Web Service Command Line Interface</strong> (AWS CLI).</p>

<p>Depending on your environment, there are different ways to <a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/cli/latest/userguide/installing.html">install AWS CLI</a>. I&rsquo;m using Mac OSX, and I prefer to install it via Homebrew <code>brew install awscli</code>.</p>

<p>Then we need to configure awscli by running: <code>aws configure</code>. You will be prompted to put your AWS Access Key Id, Secret Key, Region and Output. The following is an example:</p>

<pre><code>Access key : foo
Secret key : bar
Region     : us-west-1
Output     : json
</code></pre>

<p>We are all set. Now, I gonna show you how we copy a specific file and an entire directory from Amazon S3.</p>

<p><strong>Copy a file : </strong> <code>aws s3 cp s3://bucket_name/dir/file.png local_path</code></p>

<p><strong>Copy a directory : </strong> <code>aws s3 cp --recursive s3://bucket_name/dir local_path</code></p>

<p>The example above, I show you how to copy a file, &lsquo;file.png&rsquo;, and an entire directory, &lsquo;dir&rsquo;, by specifying <code>--recursive</code> option from Amazon S3 to your local machine or directory where you specify <code>local_path</code>.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
